Guide to the Doris Duke Memorabilia Collection, 1898-2011 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Doris Duke Memorabilia collection 1898-2011 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke, Doris, 1912-1993
28 linear feet Extent: 2,400 Items
Doris Duke was the only child of James Buchanan (J.B.) Duke, a founder of the American Tobacco Company and Duke Energy Company and a benefactor of Duke University, and Nanaline Holt Duke. Inheriting a bulk of her father's estate in 1925, which included Duke Farms in New Jersey, Rough Point in Newport, R.I., and a mansion in New York City, Doris was soon dubbed by the press as "the richest girl in the world." Although Doris did her best to live a private life, she carried on the Duke family's pattern of philanthropy by contributing to a number of public causes such as the arts, historic preservation, and the environment. Doris Duke died in October 1993 at the age of 80. In her will she left the majority of her estate to the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation. The Doris Duke Memorabilia Collection contains personal artifacts belonging to Doris Duke. The artifacts widely vary, yet tend to reflect what was important to Miss Duke including travel, philanthropy, growing orchids, and music. Of particular interest are those items from Doris Duke's childhood including scrapbooks, yearbooks, and homework assignments.
RL.00330
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research, however there are restrictions on certain materials within the collection. See Series level descriptions for more information.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Also, all of this collection is housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Doris Duke Memorabilia Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a donation from the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation in June 2009.
Historical Note
Born on November 22, 1912, Doris Duke was the only child of James Buchanan (J.B.) Duke, a founder of the American Tobacco Company and Duke Energy Company and a benefactor of Duke University, and Nanaline Holt Duke. Inheriting a bulk of her father's estate in 1925, which included Duke Farms in New Jersey, Rough Point in Newport, R.I., and a mansion in New York City, Doris was soon dubbed by the press as "the richest girl in the world." Although Doris did her best to live a private life, she carried on the Duke family's pattern of philanthropy by contributing to a number of public causes such as the arts, historic preservation, and the environment. Doris Duke died in October 1993 at the age of 80. In her will she left the majority of her estate to the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation.
Collection Overview
The Doris Duke Memorabilia Collection is part of the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation Historical Archives which were donated to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library by the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation. The collection is artificial in nature, created by combining personal artifacts belonging to Doris Duke. The artifacts widely vary, yet tend to reflect what was important to Miss Duke including travel, philanthropy, growing orchids, and music. Of particular interest are those items from Doris Duke's childhood including scrapbooks, yearbooks, and homework assignments.
The Doris Duke Memorabilia Collection covers the period 1898 to 2011 and is divided into 5 series: Awards and Tributes, Indentification and Membership Cards, Invitations, Miscellaneous, and Postcards. The materials are loosely arranged in chronological order.
Subject Headings
Cromwell, James H. R. (James Henry Roberts), b. 1896; Duke family; Duke, Doris, 1912-1993; Duke, James Buchanan, 1856-1925; Duke, Nanaline Holt Inman; International travel; Souvenirs (Keepsakes)
Related Material
Duke Family Papers, 1885-1992 (bulk 1892-1927)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Doris Duke Papers, 1798-2003 and undated (bulk 1930-1999)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Doris Duke Papers on the Duke Farms Residence, 1859-2004 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Doris Duke Papers on the Rough Point Residence, 1922-1997
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Contents of Collection
- Awards and Tributes, 1905-2007
  This series contains an assortment of materials related to the broad and varied personal activities of Doris Duke including growing and showing orchids, farming, and philanthropy.
  - Booklet, "Unveiling Washington Duke Memorial Statue" in Trinity Park, Durham, NC, 10 Jun 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Booklet, Trinity Alumni Register. Special announcement in respect for the death of Angier Buchanan Duke, class of 1905, 1923 Oct (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - In Memoriam of James Buchanan Duke from The American Tobacco Company, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - In Memoriam of James Buchanan Duke from Piedmont and Northern Railway Company, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Time Magazine with Nanaline Duke on the cover, 27 Apr 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Awards from the Horticultural Society of New York given to Duke Farms for various orchids, 1939-1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Certificate, orchids, International Flower Show, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - In Memoriam of Nanaline Holt Duke from The Duke Endowment, 1962 Apr 24 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Memorial Book to Doris Duke in memory of Nanaline Duke from Duke University. Includes photographs and correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Medal awarded to Doris Duke for "Distinguished Service in the Field of Historic Preservation" from the Preservation Society of Newport County, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Proclamation declaring December 4, 1987 Doris Duke Day in Newport, RI, 1987 Dec (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Awards from Dairylea Cooperative, Inc. to Duke Farms for production of high quality milk, 1989-1997 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Awards from Dairylea Cooperative, Inc. to Duke Farms for production of high quality milk, 1989-1997 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Mass card, Doris Duke, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Certificate of Special Congressional Recognition presented to Doris Duke (posthumously), 19 May 2007 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Appointment as member of the New Jersey Board of Control of Institutions and Agencies, 8 Jun 1938 (Box 3)
  - PETA Humanitarian Award, 1993 Jan 19 (Box 3)
  - Hillsborough Twp. Vol. Fire Co. #2 for Truck Fund, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Variety of plaques honoring Doris Duke. Includes 100,000 Mile Club, WBNX Radio (recognition for diffusion of Gospel Music), Davison College, Somerset County 4-H Club, The Hillsborough Dukes (football), 1975,1980 and undated (Box 5)
  - Variety of plaques honoring Doris Duke. Includes Hillsborough Volunteer Fire Company No. 1, Trail Blazers, C.J.D.H.I.A. (for milk and fat production) 1968, 1989-1991 and undated (Box 6)
  - First, Second and Third place ribbons for orchids at a variety of flower shows including North Jersey Orchid Society, SEPOS, Greater NY Orchid Show and South Jersey Orchid Show, 1991-1995 (Box 7)
  - Framed photograph of New Lemur Baby, Primate Center, Duke University, 1994. Given to Doris Duke in recognition of her donation. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Certificate of Appreciation from the Humane Society of the United States to the Doris Duke Foundation, 1972 Nov (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Fortieth Anniversary Commendation plaque to Doris Duke from the Duke Endowment, 1964 (Box 31)
- Identification and Membership Cards, 1933-1976
  - Copies (2) of Doris Duke's birth certificate, issued December 11, 1933 and August 26, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Checkbook, Guaranty Trust Company of New York, monogrammed with Doris Duke's initials, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Doris Duke's United Seaman's Service identification card, circa 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Doris Duke's INS U.S. War Correspondent patches, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Nazi SS patches. Found with Doris Duke's INS patches, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Patches from Doris Duke's United Seaman's Service uniform, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - United Seaman's Service patch, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Identification card, Senora Doris Duke de Rubirosa, Argentina, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Membership card, Mme Rubirosa Doris, Paris France, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Press Pass created for Doris Duke when she was on staff at the Rome Daily American Newspaper, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Driver's license issued to Doris Duke from the State of Hawaii, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Credit cards issued to Doris Duke, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Invitations, 1949-2011
  This series contains an assortment of invitations to a variety of events. Also includes invitations to openings of exhibits featuring Doris Duke or her collections.
  - Invitation to the wedding of Miss Rita Hayworth and Prince Aly Khan, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Invitation to the graduation ceremony at the Oxford Academy, Pleasantville, NJ. This was Walker P. Inman, Jr.'s graduation, 1968 Jun 20 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Invitation to ceremony which presented a National Historic Landmark Certificate to "The Duke Homestead" in Durham, North Carolina. Includes application to join the National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit catalog of the Julia Ward Howe and Hendrik Christian Anderson exhibition at the Redwood Library and Athenaeum, Newport, RI, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Invitation to Miss Duke from President and Mrs. Nixon at the White House, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Program, The White House dinner in honor of Prime Minister of the Republic of Singapore and Mrs. Lee Kuan Yew, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Presidential invitation from President and Mrs. Ford to Miss Duke for dinner, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Invitation to The Duke Ellington Memorial Fund dinner dance and cabaret starring Tony Bennett at the Rainbow Room, 1988 Oct 24 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Invitation to the dedication of the J. Carter Brown galleries at Rough Point, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Rack card, Jewelry exhibit, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Invitation and fact sheet relating to exhibit at Verdura of pieces of Doris Duke's jewelry and pieces from the Verdura Museum Collection, 2004 Feb (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Exhibit announcement for Newport Restoration Foundation's "From Jet Set to Jeans", 2005 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Invitation to opening of exhibit "Jet Set to Jeans", 2005 Jun 17 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Magazine "Jet Set to Jeans" copyright Newport Restoration Foundation, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Invitation, opening of "After the Gilded Age: The Well Dressed House in Newport", 2006 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Exhibit catalog, "The Look! Doris Duke's Day to Evening Wear 2007", 2007 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Invitation, opening of exhibit, "The Look! Doris Duke's Day to Evening Wear", 2007 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Brochure, "Rough Point: The Newport Home of Doris Duke", 2008 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Invitation to exhibit opening, "Zoo in the House: Animals in the Doris Duke Art Collection", 2008 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Rack card, "Zoo in the House: Animals in the Doris Duke Art Collection", 2008 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Pamphlet, Prescott Farm and the Samuel Whitehorne House, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Seating card, Table 1, White House Event, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Panels and banner from exhibit "Philanthropist, Environmentalist, Collector: Doris Duke and Her Estates" in the Duke University Perkins Gallery, 2011 (1 of 2) (Box 32)
  - Panels and banner from exhibit "Philanthropist, Environmentalist, Collector: Doris Duke and Her Estates" in the Duke University Perkins Gallery, 2011 (2 of 2) (Box 33)
- Miscellaneous, 1898-1990s and undated
  This series materials that did not fit into the other series. It contains a wide assortment of materials covering a wide range of topics including appointment books, scrapbooks, music composition books, newspaper clippings, and portraits of Doris Duke. Of particular interest are the caricatures by Vincenzo Zito for Doris Duke Cromwell's 26th birthday party.
  RESTRICTED: Access to folder 1 in Box 10 is restricted and requires prior written approval from the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation to view.
  - Notebook, "Masonry Work J.B. Duke's Farm" by J.L. Greenleaf, landscape architect and engineer, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Booklet, "Views of Newport R.I., circa 1906 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Book, "From Wishing Land", by Robert Louis Stevenson, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Scrapbook of Hollywood screen stars and other celebrities, circa 1920s (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Photocopy of Alletta Morris Macbean's childhood diary. Original is at the Preservation Society, RI. Doris Duke and Alletta Morris were friends, 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - List of jazz songs and movie titles handwritten by Doris Duke, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Songsheet to "There's a New Star in Heaven To-Night Rudolph Valentino", 1927 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Notebook belonging to Doris Duke, circa 1920s (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Appointment card/reminder card for meetings with Doris Duke, circa 1930s (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Newspaper article about Duke Kahanamoku, Honolulu Star-Bulletin, 1937 Jan 23 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Playbills, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Programs from the Gala Opening Night Performance of the Martha Graham Dance Company's 60th Anniversary Diamond Jubilee Season, 1986 May 27 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Program, Newport Jazz Festival, 1964 Jul 2-5 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Calling card for Mrs. James Buchanan Duke, One Thousand and Nine Fifth Avenue, circa 1910s (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Advertisement, Joe Castro Trio, Clover Records, circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Jewelry sketches by Sterle, Rene Boiven, and David Webb to add pieces to Doris Duke's jewelry collection, circa 1957 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Daily planner, A.F. Brown. Details Doris Duke's travel between her homes and around the world. Also shows the dates when Board of Trustees meetings were held for her various foundations, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Daily planner, A.F. Brown. Details Doris Duke's travel between her homes and around the world. Also shows the dates when Board of Trustees meetings were held for her various foundations, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Daily planner, A.F. Brown. Details Doris Duke's travel between her homes and around the world. Also shows the dates when Board of Trustees meetings were held for her various foundations, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Daily planner, A.F. Brown. Details Doris Duke's travel between her homes and around the world. Also shows the dates when Board of Trustees meetings were held for her various foundations, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Booklet, Newport Restoration Foundation homes, issued by NRF, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Photocopy of prayer kept under Guaryin in Palm Room, by Doris Duke, [circa late 1980s] (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Vaccination records for Doris Duke's trips to India and Thailand, 1982, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Poster for exhibition at the Palladium created by the Guerilla Girls, 1985 Oct 17 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Address book of Chandi Heffner, circa 1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Access restricted
  - Playbill from "Phantom of the Opera", 1986 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Music composition by Doris Duke, 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Postcards, pamphlets and photocopies relating to J.B. Duke's "The Doris" railway car, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Duke Farms Security Patch "Surfing Cow", circa 1990s (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Music composition by Doris Duke, circa 1990s (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Music composition by Doris Duke, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Music composition book from Falcon Lair, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Music writing book with lyrics and music written in Miss Duke's hand, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings related to Doris Duke, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Notebook containing a variety of handwritten notes and lists in Doris Duke's handwriting, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Notepad, handwritten notes by Miss Duke on antiquing, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Poem, "Shangri La" by K.B., undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Stamps of various San Francisco sites, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Story or script, "The Great Burning" (synopsis) by Rosanna Seaborn and Joseph Schull, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Travel Guides presumably from Doris Duke's travel, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Magazines with articles either about Doris Duke or her estates. Magazines include Country Life (1919 Apr), Life (1939 Mar), National Geographic (1954 May), House and Garden (1965 Jan), Vogue (1966 Nov), Architectural Digest (1976 Jul/Aug, 1977 Mar, 1994 Apr), and Gardens Architectural Digest (1983) (Box 11)
  - Memorabilia from Doris Duke's childhood. Includes three Brearley yearbooks, four composition books, and three grading books, 1922-1927 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook put together by Doris Duke which includes newspaper articles about J.B. Duke, his death, and other clippings about Doris Duke, 1925-1930s (Box 13)
  - Wood cutout of Doris Duke and Nanaline Duke, 1925-1927 (Box 14)
  - Various newspaper clippings on Doris Duke, 1933-1947 (Box 14)
  - Line drawing of Rollston Allweather Cabriolet on Packard for DDC, circa 1935-1940 (Box 14)
  - Doris Duke portrait (watercolor), 1936 (Box 14)
  - Small painting, Miss Duke, headshot with Indian earrings, circa 1944 (Box 14)
  - Ad for Pabst Blue Ribbon Beer, featuring Angier Duke, 1949 (Box 14)
  - Framed poem, "Ideals" by James Allen, undated (Box 14)
  - Ink and watercolor scenes of Paris, France. Artist unknown, undated (Box 14)
  - Plate depicting bridge at Rough Point, undated (Box 14)
  - Silhouette of Doris Duke as a child, undated (Box 14)
  - Pencil drawing of Doris Duke, 1926 May 21 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Plates 1181a and 1219 from Survey of Persian Art, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Watercolor sign for sale of orchids at Duke Farms, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers regarding the death of Rudolph Valentino, 1926 (1 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Newspapers regarding the death of Rudolph Valentino, 1926 (2 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers regarding the death of Rudolph Valentino, 1926 (3 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers regarding the death of Rudolph Valentino, 1926 (4 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Magazine articles and picture cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (1 of 8) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Magazine articles and picture cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (2 of 8) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Magazine articles and picture cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (3 of 8) (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Magazine articles and picture cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (4 of 8) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Magazine articles and picture cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (5 of 8) (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Magazine articles and picture cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (6 of 8) (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Magazine articles and picture cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (7 of 8) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Magazine articles and picture cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (8 of 8) (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (1 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (2 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (3 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Cutouts of Hollywood film stars, circa 1920s (4 of 4) (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Entertaining Book, 1936-1940 (Box 17)
  - Constitution By-laws of Spouting Rock Beach Association, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Outfits worn by Doris Duke, 1977-1978 (Box 17)
  - Glass ornament from the Boy Scouts, 1984 (Box 17)
  - Dining seating arrangement board with names of dinner guests and where they were to sit, undated (Box 17)
  - Duke Farms Employee's Liability Act Notice, 1911 (Box 17)
  - Book, "Collection of Birds at Duke Farms". Includes illustrations, 1938 (Box 18)
  - Oil painting, scene of several people in boat crossing a river, undated (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Framed portrait of Doris Duke by JA Cherry, undated (Framed-item 1)
  - Vincenzo Zito caricatures, 1938 Nov 22
    This subseries contains carictures by Vincenzo Zito for Doris Duke Cromwell's 26th birthday. Below are the names of the guests that presumably attended the party and who portrait was done by Zito.
    - Andrews, Billy (Box 19)
    - Andrews, R. (Box 19)
    - Barnes, Carmen (Box 19)
    - Bendix, Vincent (Box 19)
    - Carney, Jack (Box 19)
    - Cleary, Maury (Box 19)
    - Cromwell, Doris (Box 19)
    - Cromwell, E. (Box 19)
    - Cromwell, J.[James] (Box 19)
    - Dennis, Eleonor (Box 19)
    - Dennis, Lawrence (Box 19)
    - Doyle, Larry (Box 19)
    - Duke, Nanaline (Box 19)
    - Evans, Harry (Box 19)
    - Foy, Byron (Box 19)
    - Fray, Jacques (Box 19)
    - Glaenzer, Jules (Box 19)
    - Glendenning, Frances (Box 19)
    - Hall, Chessie (Box 19)
    - Hergesheimer, Joe (Box 19)
    - Hoffman, Dick (Box 19)
    - Holtz, Lou (Box 19)
    - Holtz, Phyllis (Box 19)
    - Howard, William (Box 19)
    - Huber, Joe (Box 19)
    - Huber, Mary (Box 19)
    - Hughes, Josephine (Box 19)
    - MacDonald, Byrnes (Box 19)
    - Mahana, Dorothy (Box 19)
    - Marsh, Mary Louise (Box 19)
    - Marston, George (Box 19)
    - McDonald, Leta (Box 19)
    - Munroe, Jack (Box 19)
    - Norman, Braddy (Box 19)
    - Norman, Eleonore (Box 19)
    - Obolenski, Serge (Box 19)
    - O'Brien, Jay (Box 19)
    - Outhwaite, Lucille (Box 19)
    - Paley, Bill (Box 19)
    - Paley, Dorothy (Box 19)
    - Rice, Ernest (Box 19)
    - Robert, Chip (Box 19)
    - Rosenblatt, Betty (Box 19)
    - Rosenblatt, Sal (Box 19)
    - Rowley, Ethel (Box 19)
    - Rowley, George (Box 19)
    - Saare, George (Box 19)
    - Sanford, L. (Box 19)
    - Sanfor, Mary (Box 19)
    - Sly, Blanche (Box 19)
    - Sly, John (Box 19)
    - Swanson, Gloria (Box 19)
    - Topping, Jane (Box 19)
    - Trumbull, Marjory (Box 19)
    - Trumbull, W. (Box 19)
    - Turtletrap, Col. (Box 19)
    - Unger, Flo (Box 19)
    - Unger, Ken (Box 19)
    - Wheterill, Edwina (Box 19)
    - Unidentified Woman (Box 19)
  - Two ceramic camel figurines, undated (Box 20)
  - Newspaper articles about Duke Gardens. Includes inscribed Oversize Box folder to hold the articles, 1964 (Box 21)
  - Pencil Drawing of Doris Duke with Horse, by Fred A. Cady, 1942 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Young Doris Duke by John D. Jasta, 1923 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Charcoal Drawing of pet dog "Mike" by Evelyn Fagan, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Nanaline H. Duke portrait by Louis Holt, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Piece created by Robert Lee Eshridgu of Johnny Gomez. Piece is signed by Johnny Gomez. Created in 1927, signed in 1937, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Triptych painting of a young Doris Duke by Mira Edgerly, 1916 (Box 26)
  - Louisville Slugger baseball bat with Doris Duke's name carved through it, undated (Box 27)
  - Autographed football to Miss Duke from the coaches and players of the Midgets football team that Miss Duke sponsored, undated (Box 28)
  - Partial weathervane presumed to be from Duke Farms. Includes arrow and "James", circa early 1900s (Box 29)
  - Reproduction of drawing of Louis Bromfield with dog by J. Anthony Wills, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Duke Family Genealogy, circa 1950s (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Ceramic tile from swimming pool at Duke Farms estate, 1933 Jan (Box 31)
- Postcards, 1900s-1990s and undated